Guide to the Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education Records 2001-2015
Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education Records
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education Records 2001-2015
4-13-4255
Cornell University. Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education Records.
7.5
Organizational records, computer files, pamphlets, correspondence, minutes, and financial records.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Files relating to the operation of the office under multiple individuals including Isaac Kramnick, Michelle Moody Adams, Laura Brown and, Rebecca Stoltzfus.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
The Vice Provost for Undergraduate Education coordinates and oversees wide areas of undergraduate education relevant to all seven undergraduate schools and colleges. Members of the office work closely with the schools and colleges and other offices across the University to promote academic success for all undergraduate students and cultivate intellectual inquiry, both in and out of the classroom.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Files relating to the operation of the office under multiple individuals including Isaac Kramnick, Michelle Moody Adams, Laura Brown and, Rebecca Stoltzfus. Files include documentation for the New Student Reading Project, Menschel Fellow Awards, the Task Force for Ethnic Studies, Committee on Race and Ethnicity, Council for Undergraduate Research, Diversity Week, Einaudi Center, Intensive English Program, English for Academic Purposes, Asian/Asian American Campus Climate Task Force, Diversity in the Curriculum, humanities, race course, September 11th programs, Phi Kappa Phi, other student services.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell University.; Cornell University -- Students.; Cornell University -- Administration.
Subjects:
English language -- Study and teaching -- Foreign speakers; Minority college students; Reading promotion; September 11 Terrorist Attacks, 2001
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Associate Dean for Undergraduate studies, 2001-09-11-2015-04-30
  Files in this series generally include minutes, Associate Deans group, and email.
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2014-2015, 2014-03-27-2015-04-30 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2013-2014, 2013-09-19-2014-05-13 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Cheating, 2013; DVD-2347 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2012-2013, 2012-08-30-2013-05-23 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Admission of Diversity goals and data; Admission and enrollment overview
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2011-2012, 2011-08-25-2012-05-17 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    Proposed academic advising timeline; extramural enrollment policies; Institutional Diversity planning; The dialogue project; international guest students; University-wide business minor at Cornell; guidelines for the submission of Academic program proposals; fellowship news
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2010-2011, 2010-04-20-2011-05-09 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    Research course analysis; Advising Technology solutions working group; Internal transfer memo; undergraduate research project; student assembly resolution
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2009-2010, 2009-08-27-2010-05-20 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Internal transfer policy changes; circular disability compliance responsibilities; Health excuse policy
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2008-2009, 2008-08-28-2009-05-21 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    Parental notification for alcohol and other drugs cases; charge for educational programs and services plan; reorganization outline for Cornell Undergraduate admissions
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2007-2008, 2007-08-22-2008-09-26 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    Periodic review Report (June 1, 2006); Explore 2007 (intellectual exploration with faculty)
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2006-2007, 2006-07-31-2007-05-17 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    Assessing student learning and institutional effectiveness (pamphlet); Comparative analysis of FERPA-family educational right to privacy Act (buckley amendments) policies for cornell and peer institutions (packet)
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2005-2006, 2005-04-27-2006-03-28 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    Senior survey; preliminary report of the academic advising committee; Middle states periodic review report milestone
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2004-2005, 2004-01-13-2005-04-27 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    Cornell University satisfactory academic progress guidelines for undergraduates financial aid applicants; first year family weekend pamphlet.
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2003-2004, 2003-08-21-2004-04-28 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Survey of faculty interaction with undergraduate students
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2002-2003, 2002-09-10-2003-07-24 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    Graduation rate report (1900-1995); Survey research presentation background
  - Associate Deans for Undergraduate studies 2001-2002, 2001-09-11-2002-03-26 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Resolution recommendation that each course syllabus include reference to the Cornell university code of Academic integrity; Kendall S. Carpenter Memorial Advising Award for programs.
- Cornell University Press, 1972-11-29-2000-02-16
  - Cornell University Press 3/95 - 6/97, 1982-10-29-1997-06-25 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    Report of the Community to review the University Press; Memo's; December 31, 1995 Quarterly Review Agenda; Cornell University Press Sage House five year plan
  - Cornell University Press, 1982-10-18-1994-11-21 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    Memo's; Report of the Committee to Review the Cornell University Press; Observation on the C.U. Press; Statement of income and publishing; Job offer to John Ackerman; University Press Audit Report
  - Ackerman Evaluation, 1992-04-22-1993-04-27 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    Memo's; Performance evaluation; Effective supervision survey
  - CU Press Kearns, 1991-09-16-1993-10-22 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    Performance appraisal form; performance evaluation form
  - Archives Pickup Report, 1972-11-29-1984-03-14 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    Cornell University Archives pickup Report
  - CIS/ Faculty Senate Task Force, 1999-09-27-2000-02-16 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    Emails; Comments on the Final Report of the Task Force on CIS; Rewrite of Computing and Information Sciences Task Force; Final report of the Task Force on Computing and Information Science
  - Transition of Faculty to Emeritus Status, 1996-11-12-1998-05-19 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    Retirement legislation; Proposed Policy on Transition of Faculty ti Emeritus Status; Provost's statement; Memorandum; New tenure-track appointments total University
  - Transition Com. Report, 1997-03-31-1997-04-15 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    Provost's Committee on the transition of Faculty to Emeritus Status
  - Graduate and Professional Education Task Force, 1995-04-19-1995-07-05 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    Cornell University Task force on Graduate and Professional Education; Letters
  - Task Force on Graduate Education, 1993-03-05-1995-05-31 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    Final report of the task force on Graduate and Professional Education; Memorandum
  - Committee on Tenure Review, 1997-09-08-1997-12-09 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    Minutes of meeting on Tenure Decisions; Memo; Guidelines governing reviews for tenure
  - Guidelines Governing Reviews For Tenure, 1995-03-16-1995-12-14 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Guidelines Governing Reviews For Tenure; Cornell University Faculty Handbook
- Freshman Book Projects, 2001-12-16-2015-08
  Files in this series generally include email, invoices, room assignments, memos, agendas, meeting minutes, study questions, student essay materials, orientations and other programs and paper items related to events such as postcards and bookmarks.
  - Book Project 2002: Frankenstein, 2001-12-16-2004
    - Frankenstein 2002: Mailing to students, study guide, articles, 2002-06-11-2002-10 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Frankenstein 2002: Press, 2002-02-06-2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Frankenstein 2002: Library and city involvement, 2001-12-16-2002-08-15 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Book Project 2003: Antigone, 2003-03-30-2004-03-16
    - Antigone, 2003-05-03-2004-03-16 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      Includes Barton panel, Time warner and video, facilitator problems and distribution.
    - Antigone: orientation handworks, 2003-08-19-2003-08-21 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Antigone: Barton programs 4000 pieces, 2003-08-22-2003-08-24 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Antigone: Articles; study questions, 2003-03-30-2003-06-12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Book Project 2004: The Trial, 2004-02-26-2004-12-06
    - Book Project for fall 2004 The trial, 2004-06-15-2004-12-06 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Includes group assignments, descriptive results and some handwritten notes
    - Facilitator clan lists for The Trial, Undated; CD-3470 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - The Trial: Trustee mailing, 2004-08-25-2004-08-27 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - The Trial: Feedback, 2002-05-03-2005-08-11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Includes online evaluation summary
    - The Trial/2004, 2004-02-26-2004-07-26 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - The Trial: Facilitator orientation, 2004-08-17-2004-08-19 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - The Trial: Small groups, 2004-07-13-2004-08-31 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Book Project 2005: Things Fall Apart, 2005-02-08-2005-12-22
    - Book Project 2005, 2005-02-08-2005-12-22 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Includes feedback, facilitator comments, billing for panel setup at Barton, CIT service agreement, and 2004 reading book online evaluation summary.
    - Book Project 2005: Essay Prize, 2005-08-2005-09-10 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Book Project 2005: Achebe visit, 2005-02-14-2005-09-15 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      Includes event ticket; dinner with Chinua Achebe invitation(5); Dinner menu
    - Book Project 2005: Freshmen book panel and Achebe lecture, 2005; DVD-2332-2333 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      2 copies.
  - Book Project 2006: Gatsby, 2005-07-28-2006-08-28
    - The Great Gatsby: 2007, 2005-09-04-2006-08-28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - The Great Gatsby: Maps and building Index for campus building guide, 2005; CD-3469 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Great Gatsby book forum, 2005; DVD-2330-2331 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Gatsby: Essay winners, 2005-09-11-2006-04-10 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Gatsby: Barton Panel, 2005-07-28-2006-03-10 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Book Project 2007: The pickup, 2007-01-23-2007-10-26
    - The Pickup, 2007-06-18-2007-10-26 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The Pickup: Cybertower with Michele Moody-Adams, Undated; DVD-2334 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - The Pickup, 2007-08-19-; DVD-2335-2336 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Book project 2007, 2007-01-23-2007-10-24 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Book Project 2008: Lincoln at Gettysburg, 2008-02-13-2009-06-11
    - Lincoln at Gettysburg, 2008-02-13-2009-06-11 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Lincoln at Gettysburg - Garry Wills, 2008; DVD-2337-2338 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Gary Willis, 2008-08-18-2008-10-06 (Box 1, Folder 23)
      Includes details about dining, board, and travel.
    - Book Project 2008, 2007-10-24-2008-02-06 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      Includes 2004 and 2006 survey and an invoice.
    - Lincoln essays, 2008-10-30-2008-12-15 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      Includes congratulatory messages from President Skorton to winners
  - Book project 2009: The Grapes of Wrath, 2009-08-23-2009-10-16
    - The Grapes of Wrath, 2008-10-15-2009-10-16 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Grapes of Wrath, DVD-2339 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Grapes of Wrath Post Mortem, 2009-08-28-2009-09-08 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Grapes of Wrath Essays, 2009-10-08-2009-10-08 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Book Project 2010: Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep?, 2010-01-13-2010-08-31
    - Do Androids Dream of Electric Sheep, 2010-01-13-2010-08-31 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Book Project 2011:, 2011-02-14-2011-11-30
    - Homer and Langley, 2011-02-14-2011-11-30 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      Includes website analysis
  - Book Project 2012: The Life Before US, 2011-2014
    - Book Project 2012: The Life Before US, 2013-9-16-2014-06-03 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Book Project 2012: The Life Before US, 2011-10-16-2012-10-31 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Book Project 2013: When the Emperor Was Divine, 2013-2014
    - When the Emperor Was Divine, 2013-03-28-2014-06-03 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Emperor Essays, 2013-08 -2013-12-09
  - Brook Project 2014: Clash of Civilizations Over an Elevator In Piazza Vittorio, 2014-2015
    - Clash of Civilizations…, 2014-05-07-2015-03-11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Book Project 2015: Slaughterhouse Five, 2015
    - Slaughterhouse Five, 2015-08 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Awards and Honors, 1997-12-31-2016-12-12
  - Menschel Fellow Awards, 2002-2010
    Formerly known as Provost Awards or Menschel Prize. Files include candidate lists and award winners, letters to award winners and CVs of candidates.
    - Menschel Prize 2003, 2002-05-11-2003-04-03 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Menschel Prize 2004, 2004-02-24-2004-03-03 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Menschel Prize 2004, 2003-02-18-2004-05-06 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Menschel Prize 2005, 2004-11-01-2005-06-20 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Menschel Prize 2006, 2006-01-25-2006-03-17 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Menschel Prize 2007, 2006-01-24-2007-05-10 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Menschel Prize 2008, 2008-01-28-2008-04-02 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Menschel Prize 2009, 2009-03-09-2009-04-23 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Menschel Prize 2010, 2010-02-01-2010-04-30 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Menschel Prize 2003-2010, 2003-04-2010-04 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Kendall Carpenter Memorial Advising Awards and Dinners, 2002-2014
    Files include nomination, recommendation, and award letters, packets, emails, event programs, and student writings.
    - Carpenter nominations 2002, 2002-02-04-2002-05-01 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Carpenter awards 2003, 2003-02-04-2003-09-17 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Awards Dinner 2003, 2002-11-08-2003-05-07 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Carpenter Awards 2004, 2004-02-09-2004-06-17 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Carpenter Awards Dinner 2004, 2004-05-10-2003-09-23 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Carpenter Awards 2005 Master list, 2004-03-17-2005-04-25 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Carpenter Awards 2005, 2005-03-11-2005-06-08 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Awards Dinner 2005, 2002-02-26-2005-03-25 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Carpenter Awards 2006 Master list, 2004-06-02-2006-03-20 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Carpenter Awards 2006, 2005-03-08-2006-08-03 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Awards Dinner 2006, 2005-07-28-2006-04-07 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Carpenter Awards 2007 Master List, 2007-02-22-2007-06-02 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Carpenter Award 2007, 2006-02-24-2007-04-18 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Awards Dinner 2007/2008, 2007-04-24-2008-05-28 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Carpenter Awards 2008 Master list, 2008-02-11-2008-03-23 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Carpenter Advising Award 2008, 2007-02-05-2008-05-13 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Carpenter Awards 2009 Master List, 2000-07-11-2009-03-25 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Carpenter Advising Award 2009, 2009-01-20-2009-14-30 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Carpenter Awards 2010 Master List, 2009-02-15-2009-03-10 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Carpenter Advising Award 2010, 2006-02-17-2010-04-14 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Carpenter Awards 2011 Master List, 2011-02-10-2011-03-08 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Carpenter Awards 2011, 2011-01-25-2011-04-05 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Carpenter Awards 2012 Master List, 2012-01-28-2012-03-01 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Carpenter Awards 2012, 2011-01-06-2011-04-05 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Carpenter Awards 2013 Master List, 2013-02-11-2013-03-06 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Carpenter Advising Award 2013, 2013-02-15-2013-05-15 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Carpenter Awards 2014 Master List, 2014-02-14-2014-03-08 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Carpenter Advising Award 2013, 2014-04-07-2014-04-07 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Rhodes Professorship, 1997-12-31-2016-12-12
    Files generally include nomination and recommendation letters, reimbursement forms, invoices, email, memos, tax forms, schedules of events, CVs
    - General Anthony Zinni, 2007-06-12-2010-05-11 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Prospects for Peace in the Middle East - Lecture, 2008-04-24-; DVD-2340 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The New World Order - General Anthony Zinni - Lecture, 2008-04-15-; DVD-2341 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - R. Spencer Wells, 2009-06-04-2010-03-25 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Edward Scolnick, 1999-01-07-2002-04-03 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Includes photographs, and newspaper article.
    - John Pilger/ Rhodes, 2002-02-19-2004-10-21 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Pilger Payments, 2004-08-31-2004-11-02 (Box 7, Folder 11)
      Receipts, bills, and ax forms
    - John Pilger, 2003-2004 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Paying the PRICE: Killing the Children of Iraq, 2000; V-9866 (Box 7, Folder 12)
      Directed by John Pilger
    - Breaking the silence Truth and lies in the war on Terror, 2003; DVD-2342 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Richard Meier/ Rhodes, 2000-03-05-2000-10-23 (Box 7, Folder 13)
      Includes photographs, posters and Meier biographical information
    - Thomas Simons, 2002-11-26-2006-08-07 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - McKinney: Letters Re: Appointment, 2003-08-21-2003-11-14 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      Includes letters and emails of disapproval for McKinney's nomination.
    - McKinney: Press Coverage on Visit Sun, Chronicle, Ithaca Journal, 2003-08-21-2003-11-24 (Box 7, Folder 16)
      Cornell Daily Sun articles of the McKinney appointment
    - Cynthia McKinney/ Rhodes, 2002-08-22-2003-06-30 (Box 7, Folder 17)
      Additional information for the professorial nominations and a photograph of Congresswoman McKinney
    - Robert Parris Moses, 2006-06-12-2008-10-18 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Janet Reno February 2-14, 2003, 2001-02-09-2003-11-13 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      Includes Cornell Sun articles on professor Reno and other newspaper pages
    - Reno, 2004-09-30-2004-11-17 (Box 7, Folder 20)
      Includes Cornell Daily Sun paper from November 9, 2004
    - Janet Reno / Rhodes, 2001-02-01-2005-10-07 (Box 7, Folder 21)
      Includes letter of re-appointment, Cornell Sun articles and other newspaper clippings.
    - Temple Grandin Rhodes Appointment, 2004-12-11-2010-01-29 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Includes posters, newspaper articles, and handwritten letter from Grandin
    - Animal Behavior, Autism, and Welfare Auditing - Lecture, 2006-02-15; DVD-2343-2344 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      DVD and Master DVD
    - Animal Behavior, Autism, and Welfare Auditing - Lecture, 2006-02-15; V-9867 (Box 7, Folder 22)
      Camera original. DVCPro/DP121
    - Bill Nye, 2000-11-28-2006-07-31 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Includes letters in support of tenure extension, Cornell News articles, and photographs.
    - Ramaswami Balaburbramaniam, 2011-10-10-2016-12-12 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Peter Eisenman, 2007-10-09-2010-03-18 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Memory and Memorial, 2009-02-17; DVD-2345 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - RHODES: McKinney/Pilger, 2003-05-08-2003-10-13 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Rhodes Selection Committee 1 July 2009 -31 May 2012, 2009-04-28 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Welcome letter to members of the committee
    - Rhodes pre-proposal Fall 2011, 2011-09-28-2011-11-02 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Rhodes Full Proposals: Fall 2011-Spring 2012, 2011-10-11-2012-02-14 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Rhodes Full Proposals: Fall 2009 -Spring 2010, 2010-01-25-2010-04-23 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Rhodes pre-proposal Fall 2009, 2009-10-03-2009-11-20 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Includes information about the internship program for veterinary Students 20th Anniversary issue
    - Rhodes Professor: getting out the call for nominations, 2003-09-03-2009-02-23 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Meetings, 2004-06-10-2004-11-05 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Rhodes Professorship, 2004-05-03-2004-09-18 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Rhodes: Website, 2000-07-20-2000-08-23 (Box 8, Folder 13)
      Includes photocopy of the website
    - Rhodes: employee ID info, 2002-06-24-2003-10-17 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Rhodes: 1999-2000 Financial Statement/ Annual Report, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Rhodes: 2000-2001 Financial Statement/ Annual Report, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Rhodes: 2001-2002 Financial Statement/ Annual Report, 2001-2002 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Rhodes: 2003-2004 Financial Statement/ Annual Report, 2003-03-17-2003-06-23 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Rhodes: 2001-2002 Budget Submission, 2001-03-19-2001-10-02 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Logo-Booklet Rhodes '56, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Rhodes '56 booklet Alumni Reunion 6/01, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Minutes of the selection committee 1999-2003, 2000-03-07-2003-03-13 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Rhodes: founding documents, 1st appointment, 1997-12-31-2004-05-04 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Rhodes endowment History, 2001-02-12-2002-10-27 (Box 8, Folder 24)
      Includes financial summary and invested fund statement.
- Diversity and Ethnic Initiatives, 2002-03-04-2006
  Files include email, minutes, outreach packets and handbooks, statistics, and news articles.
  - Task Force for Ethnic Studies 2001-2002, 2002-04-29-2002-05-17 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Includes mission statements, proposal, email, and final report.
  - Task Force for Ethnic Studies 2002-2003, 2002-09-03-2003-05-12 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Task Force for Ethnic Studies 2002-2003 (continued), 2002-03-04-2004-10-17 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Committee on Race and Ethnicity, 2003-07-22-2004-09-28 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Includes email and list of participants.
  - Research on Race and Ethnicity Curriculum, 2002-12-02-2004-11-09 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    Includes curriculum from other universities
  - Diversity Week, 2002-02-11-2002-04-22 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Intensive English Program (IEP)/East Asia Program (EAP) and English for Academic Purposes (ENGAP), 2004-01-26-2004-12-07 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Cornell Interactive Theatre Ensemble (CITE ): One Vision Many Voices (OVMV) 2005-2006, 2005-05-24-2005-09-13 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    Diversity training files
  - Tapestry, 2006- (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Tapestry of Possibilities: Diversity at Cornell, 2006; DVD-2346 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - CITE, 2003-05-21-2003-08-14 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    "One Vision Many Voices" fall 2014 program dates and files
  - Freshman Diversity Initiative "One Vision Many Voices", 2004-06-21-2004-09-30 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Asian/Asian American Campus Climate Task Force Report, 2004-10-26-2004-10-26 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Diversity in the Curriculum: A guide to Undergraduate courses, Date unknown (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Race Course Lunches, 2004-01-29-2004-05-13 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    Receipts and invoices
  - Race Course, 2003-07-07-2004-05-17 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Cornell Alumni mentoring Students Program, 2003-01-05-2005-04 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    Invoice; program description; Response to survey
  - Minority Mentor Program, 2003-03-20-2004-10-21 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Office of Minority Educational Affairs (OMEA), 2001-03-2009-09-17
  - Minority Education and Committee On Special Education Projects (COSEP), 2001-03-2002-02-05 (Box 4, Folder 13)
    Includes resident's council list; COFHE (Consortium on financing higher education) graduation rate study; Summary update: Progress toward diversity and inclusion (booklet); Minority affairs council
  - Minority Program Inventory, 2003-02-12-2008-05-23 (Box 4, Folder 14)
    Includes Pre-freshmen program statistics 1999-2002
  - OMEA, 2009-01-2009-09-17 (Box 4, Folder 15)
    Includes information about the Albert Einstein College of Medicine of Yeshiva University Minority Student Summer Research Opportunity Program.
- Student Services, 2001-07-01-2006-02-02
  - Council for Undergraduate Research, 2001-07-01-2002-01-18
    - CUR, 2001-09-07-2002-03-29 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Undergraduate Research, 2001-07-01-2002-01-18 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Humanities Seminar, 2001-08-28-2006-02-02
    - Humanities Seminar, 2001-08-28-2001-09-05 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      Includes a list of participants in Mellon Humanities Seminar Fall 2001